LOUIS MEDINA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

+1 909 767 3660



louism2@uci.edu



Mulited States, Pomona, 91767



in Louis Medina

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

- PHP
- SQL(Postgres)
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- ImageMagick
- Ghostscript
- ZPL
- Docker
- LINUX Shell
- Bitbucket

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts

Business Economics University of California - Irvine 2014 - 2019

High School Diploma

Pomona High School 2010 - 2014

PROFILE

Software developer with 2 years of experience who desires to expand skill set. Currently supports warehouse management software development in a third party logistics corporation. Experienced in PHP, SQL, Javascript, and several other programming/scripting languages on both the front-end and back-end. Proficient in working collaboratively within IT environments to achieve project timelines and milestones. Strategic, intuitive, and systems oriented thinker.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / DATA ANALYST / HELP DESK

Motivational Fulfillment and Logistics Services | 2022 - Current

Primary responsibilities include management and development of software projects. Other key duties include database management, frequent coordination with the senior software management team, and participation in IT briefings to C-level personnel. Secondary responsibilities consist of daily ticket closures; tasks range from user setup to report creation and nightly report automation.

- Created inventory migration tool to seamlessly facilitate transition from obsolete warehouse management system to current.
- Designed and developed KPI dashboards, both internal and client facing.
- Crafted data queries from header to detail level for day to day operations use.
- Provided outstanding ticket resolution rate with shortest response time in department.

SERVICE MANAGER / BILLING MANAGER

Fuel Pros Inc. | 2021 - 2022

Oversaw management of service and billing departments. Duties included a mixture of internal administration and client facing relations.

- Reached yearly revenue percentage growth target of 10% by making use of inter-department collaboration and diplomacy.
- Prioritized service calls based on level of urgency, technician certifications, and time constraints.
- Creation and tracking of invoices/quotes.

COLLEGE MATHEMATICS TUTOR(Simultaneous)

Freelancer | 2021-2022

Operated as an independent tutor in college algebra, trigonometry, calculus, and logic.

- Created study plans based on class syllabus and forecasted exam questions.
- Provided personally crafted lectures and problem sets.

LOUIS MEDINA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

- Inter-department Diplomacy
- Deadlining
- Wireframing
- Goal Setting
- Business Writing
- Project Planning
- Task Delegation
- Operations

EXTRA

Dean's List Fall Quarter

University of California / 2018

Dean's List Winter Quarter

University of California / 2018

INTERESTS

- Martial Arts
- Philosophy
- Reading
- Guitar
- Competitive Gaming

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

LOGISTICS COORDINATOR

The Gilbert Company | 2019-2021

Ensured efficient load distributions across fleet resources while balancing operator satisfaction, off duty time, and client desires.

- Coordinated between dispatch, warehouse, and billing departments.
- Data entry and tabulation, creation and oversight of operator routes.

ASSISTANT MANAGER/ KEY HOLDER

Built to Fight Industries | 2018-2019

Acted as principal authority on the storefront guaranteeing customer satisfaction and meeting of sales goals. Worked with clientele ranging from beginners to combat sports professionals.

- Coordinated warehouse and storefront via management of: inventory, delivery times, and miscellaneous organizational conflicts.
- Gave consultation tailored to individual client needs.
- Creation of end of day documents; reported returns, sales, and sales projections.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.